<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kninja 🌩</title>
    <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kninja 🌩</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 07:28:39 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pantsufan.github.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using An Ultrawide Monitor</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/ultrawide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 07:28:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/ultrawide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More Pixels Baby&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first monitor had a 4:3 aspect ratio unlike, most monitors in 2012. So my parents brought me a new 16:9 LG monitor, although it was just above HD resolution, I used it till 2019 which&amp;rsquo;s, a lot of time and, I was getting into video editing so, I need a 1080p monitor. After a few days got one of the budget offerings from BenQ with an IPS panel, the upgrade was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was my earlier experience now shifting, my focus on my ultrawide experience. In 2020 I got myself the most powerful laptop that I could afford at that time, Asus TUF A15 with Ryzen 7. I could do most of the stuff within less time but, I always dreamed of having a setup with either two monitors or an ultrawide. For the first four months after getting a laptop, I never complained of not having a bigger screen but, then there came Amazon&amp;rsquo;s annual sale in my country. I saw the deal on an LG ultrawide monitor with HDR for $248. Ultimately my dream became a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first impression about the monitor was the size of it was massive compared to my previous monitors. (Fun Fact: In 2018, I got myself a custom-made desk with space to accompany an ultrawide setup).
The HDR content is stunning to look at and, the inbuilt speakers are so loud that they removed the need to buy a soundbar. The only caveat is while watching regular 16:9 videos there, are black bars on the left and right sides but, after few days, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even bother me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part of using an ultrawide is the ability to use multiple applications on a single screen. My workflow is simple, just using each half of the display to do a single task. For example, while building a web app, I could write the code in one half and preview it in the other half. It eliminates the need to switch windows or minimize the browser. Now with the ultrawide setup, my workflow has improved to a new level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;update&#34;&gt;Update:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past 14 days, I was regularly posting on this blog. But now, I have decided to take some time off to learn more about the topics that interest me. Whenever I discover something new, I post it here so guys can have a look at it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tackling Your Major Task</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/tackling-your-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 09:31:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/tackling-your-tasks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Make Your Morning Productive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Twain once said&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s your job to eat a frog, it&amp;rsquo;s best to do it first thing in the morning. And If it&amp;rsquo;s your job to eat two frogs, it&amp;rsquo;s best to eat the biggest one first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-eat-a-frog&#34;&gt;How to Eat a Frog?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The frog is that one thing you have on your to-do list that is biggest and difficult to achieve and for which you don&amp;rsquo;t have any motivation. Eating the frog at the start would provide you with a sense of accomplishment at the beginning of your day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-that-damn-frog&#34;&gt;Find That Damn Frog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding the frog which, is crucial to you, can be done with the help of a simple question. What are things you don’t want to do but actually need to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;taking-action&#34;&gt;Taking Action&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, my biggest, frog was to practice web development. Ever since I started to do it as the first thing after waking up I could get a lot of stuff done in a short period of time. Interestingly enough I have also noticed that I  am in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kj1hLFSORTQ&#34;&gt;state of flow&lt;/a&gt; and I don&amp;rsquo;t have any sense of time whats so ever. My day usually begins at 6 AM and for the next 2 hours, I am on my laptop either doing web development or reading on topics that interest me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned that practice is the key to mastering any skill. Tackling your major task first thing each morning will help you stay focused, productive, and motivated to achieve more. Eat that damn frog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Comment Section To My Blog</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 06:04:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/comments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its Simple and Easy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://joelchrono12.netlify.app/adding-comments-blog/&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;, I also wanted to add a comment section to my blog. But the first hurdle was how to get it working and which service to use. Instead of banging my head against the wall, I looked up at Hugo&amp;rsquo;s documentation on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/comments/#comments-alternatives&#34;&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;. Over there, I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://utteranc.es/&#34;&gt;Utterances&lt;/a&gt;, an open-source, GitHub comments widget built on GitHub Issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utterances specify how to set up the comment section in a very straightforward manner. But there was a problem once I did the initial set up and then went back to my blog to notice that the widget was not appearing. To fix this problem, I went to their GitHub issues and found someone having the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/utterance/utterances/issues/461&#34;&gt;same issue&lt;/a&gt;. After the following solution that was listed over there, the comment section widget started to appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There you go, my short exploration journey of adding a comment section on this blog. Let me know what do you think in the comment section!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recreating My Project Using NextJS</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/recreate-with-nextjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 06:14:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/recreate-with-nextjs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Find Your Waifu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been using React for my projects for more than a year now. Eventually, I wanted to try out &lt;a href=&#34;https://nextjs.org/&#34;&gt;Next.js&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, I needed to recreate my second React project since I lost the first one in distro-hopping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project which I am going to discuss in this post is called Ayame. Ayame is an anime listing website that fetches its data from a &lt;a href=&#34;https://jikan.moe/&#34;&gt;Jikan REST API&lt;/a&gt; that, in turn, is an unofficial MyAnimeList API. The reason why I needed to switch to Next.js was because of its routing system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first shared the original project with my friends, some had never heard about anime. This time around, there was the need to show the top anime on the front page. Two other pages would handle searching for the anime and ongoing seasonal anime. When the design got decided, I sat down to work on it. It took me more than 3 hours to finish the initial version of the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how it looked before&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.postimg.cc/L6DzqQPX/Screenshot-2021-02-11-Ayame.png&#34; alt=&#34;Ayame Original&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how it looks now&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.ibb.co/Sx6Bxv6/ayame.png&#34; alt=&#34;Ayame New&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sum it all up, I am happy with the new layout and how it turned out to be. If anyone has any suggestions for improving the website, contact me on Mastodon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original version of Ayame: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ayame.surge.sh/&#34;&gt;https://ayame.surge.sh/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new version of Ayame: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ayamev2.vercel.app/&#34;&gt;https://ayamev2.vercel.app/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Fedora For The First Time</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/fedora-lxde/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 06:08:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/fedora-lxde/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fedora LXDE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first experience with Fedora was in college. Those computers were running on an older version of Fedora. Recently, I thought of using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://spins.fedoraproject.org/en/lxde/&#34;&gt;LXDE&lt;/a&gt; version of Fedora since that was the interface that I had seen in college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding the download link of LXDE took me some time because it came under the section of the spins. When the downloading of the ISO finished, I made an instance in the virtual machine to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first difference that I noticed about the Fedora was it came with an Anaconda installer that was simple and easy to use. The installation time was under 10 minutes. To my surprise, the bootup time in the VM was quick compared to my previous Linux distributions. The first thing which everybody should do after installing any distro is to update its packages. Out of the box, there was an update of 643 MB with 540 packages that needed an update. On the first boot, the memory usage was around 500 MB out of 4 GB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another major difference that caught my attention was the package manager that Fedora uses that is different from Ubuntu. It uses dnf as its package manager. The LXDE version ships with Midori, a lightweight browser. I thought of using Midori as a daily but ended up using Brave. The LXDE version came with Openbox as its window manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sum up everything the main reason I chose LXDE over any other desktop environment was that LXDE was the very first desktop environment that I used in my life so obviously, I had a soft corner for it in my heart. Fedora was the medium to time travel back in my childhood where I tinkered around with my computers and to get back the memory of installing my first Linux distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(To those who are curious which distro it was the answer is Lubuntu)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eleventy My New Love</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/eleventy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 06:06:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/eleventy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A simpler static site generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been a fan of static site generators for a while. I have used Hugo, Jekyll, and even Gatsby. But, at last, I decided to settle on Hugo for my blog. Recently, I discovered this new kid on the block called Eleventy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I discovered Eleventy, I wanted to try it, so I looked up its documentation but couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand my way around it. Ultimately I decided to lookup on YouTube for tutorials to get started (I am a visual learner). I went with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j8mJrhhdHWc&#34;&gt;Jason Lengstorf video with Eleventy creator Zach Leatherman&lt;/a&gt;. The video explained most of the concepts, and then I could start my journey with Eleventy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I recreated my blog alongside &lt;a href=&#34;https://simplecss.org/&#34;&gt;Simple CSS&lt;/a&gt; that gave the site a minimal look, and also, there is an RSS plugin for Eleventy. Lastly, I could navigate through the documentation to know more about Eleventy. I ended up not using the recreated blog since I was happy with my current setup but, at least it gives me relief that in the future, I could build a blog from the ground up with the help of Eleventy and any CSS framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.ibb.co/bsR06Mq/Web-capture-9-2-2021-858.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;blog&#34; title=&#34;Recreated Blog&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop here. The next day I sat down to create my portfolio page so, I used Eleventy and &lt;a href=&#34;https://getuikit.com/&#34;&gt;UIkit&lt;/a&gt;. The final output was just as how I thought about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.ibb.co/hC3DqQw/Web-capture-9-2-2021-8542.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;portfolio&#34; title=&#34;Portfolio&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to find a static site generator that can fulfill your needs, then have a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamstack.org/generators/&#34;&gt;StaticGen&lt;/a&gt;. I have not covered every bit of Eleventy and, what makes it different from others to know more about that, read the introductory post by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zachleat.com/web/introducing-eleventy/&#34;&gt;Zach Leatherman&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create A Gemini Capsule</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/gemini-capsule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 06:16:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/gemini-capsule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New Internet Protocol&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past few days, the term Gemini has been trending on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gemini protocol is an application layer protocol for distributed hypertext information systems that provides access to simple, primarily textual documents in Gemini space. This is done with contemporary technologies such as TLS, thereby improving privacy and user agency relative to the Web. (Taken from Wikipedia)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very first question that arrived at me while exploring Gemini was how I set up a mirrored version of this very blog and, then I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://gemlog.blue/&#34;&gt;gemlog&lt;/a&gt;. It provides an easy way to keep a gemlog (journal) over the Gemini protocol. For creating an account you don&amp;rsquo;t require any identifying information. Pick a username of your choice with a strong password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to access your newly created gemlog you need a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gemini.circumlunar.space/clients.html&#34;&gt;Gemini client&lt;/a&gt;. The one which I use is &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmi.skyjake.fi/lagrange/&#34;&gt;Lagrange&lt;/a&gt; a GUI client with cross-platform support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;gemini://gemlog.blue/users/kninja&#34;&gt;My Gemini Capsule&lt;/a&gt; (All of my posts will be available over here)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve as a Writer</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/writer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 06:00:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/writer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every writer can get better, and no writer is perfect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The definition of writing can be different for many. For me, it&amp;rsquo;s putting my ideas and thoughts on a sheet of paper. I spend most of my time in front of digital screens, that&amp;rsquo;s why the sheet of paper interchanged with a blank document. Ever since I came across the 100 days of offload challenge, I wanted to test myself as a writer. I don&amp;rsquo;t aim to be an author. It&amp;rsquo;s just that I want to get better at expressing myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried blogging previously but, I failed at it, not because of a lack of ideas. I feared what people might think of my posts. In December 2020, I decided to reinstate my blogging journey with a fresh coat of new ideas. This very blog was born out of those unsuccessful ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started my 100 days challenge, I learned something new every day. I am noticing the difference in my writing style. I adapted forward my old notes from books and blog posts into my very own blog posts. So, don&amp;rsquo;t think of yourself as someone who can&amp;rsquo;t do anything in life. We all start somewhere with small and humble beginnings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Computer Code Is Different</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/reading-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 06:27:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/reading-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;But Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning a computer programming language is somewhat similar to that of learning a new language to speak. According to &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.mit.edu/2020/brain-reading-computer-code-1215&#34;&gt;MIT neuroscientists&lt;/a&gt; reading computer code doesn&amp;rsquo;t involve the region of the brain which is responsible for language processing. Instead, it activates distributed network called the &lt;strong&gt;multiple demand network&lt;/strong&gt;, which also gets activated during solving a mathematical problem or a crossword.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of computer code, the brain uses &lt;strong&gt;multiple areas&lt;/strong&gt; of multiple demand network. Multiple demand network gets activated only when there is a need to store more information and while performing mental tasks. The MIT team also found out that reading computer code appears to activate both the left and right sides of the multiple demand network. There is no finding of some region exclusively devoted to programming, but there is some possibility in those who have more coding experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of Page Size</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/page-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 06:08:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/page-size/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Page Size Matters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days back, I came across the &lt;a href=&#34;https://512kb.club/&#34;&gt;512KB club&lt;/a&gt; that lists websites whose uncompressed page size is less than 512KB. I decided to give it a try. To my surprise, my page size was just under 400KB but, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t thrilled with the result. So I decided to cut down even more so, I set out on this adventurous journey of reducing my page size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.postimg.cc/hjgSs1KQ/prev-min.png&#34; alt=&#34;Previous page size&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got rid of unwanted JavaScript code and CSS that helped me reduce the page size by 40-50 KB. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t thrilled enough so, I got back again to debug what was causing the enormous page size. Luckily, I got my answer, and that was my favicon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A favicon is a small, iconic image that represents your website. My blog&amp;rsquo;s favicon was taking around 300 KB, due to which every time I requested my blog, the favicon was adding its extra size to the final page size. Upon discovering this issue, I redid my favicon as 32x32 instead of the previous 256x256.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicated fix massively improved the page size. Now, my blog&amp;rsquo;s uncompressed page size is 22.8 KB compared to the original 335.6 KB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.postimg.cc/3J7DYCKL/new-Result-min.png&#34; alt=&#34;Current page size&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the solution to our problem is right in front of us but, we don&amp;rsquo;t attempt to look at it thereby, wasting time and energy on something different.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaming Laptop Are Becoming Boring</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/gaming-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 06:14:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/gaming-laptop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fast but aliented&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, gaming is a medium to enjoy and not yell at friends like most of my friends do. I got myself a gaming laptop as a birthday gift. For the first few weeks, I played some of my favorite games and enjoyed every second of them. But I missed something that made me appreciate it even more and, that was playing it on low-end hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me get this point clear. All the systems which I owned till now were less than $300 in cost. Which also introduced me to the world of Linux since they were performing poorly on Windows. When I shifted to a $1000 laptop, I could feel the difference in performance, but that was all it for me. I could render my videos faster, play modern gaming titles &amp;amp; compile code quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when it came to gaming, I missed reading and watching tutorials online to get that last bit of FPS from the game on my older hardware. That was pure enjoyment for me since I could notice the difference it was making to the game after applying the tweaks. Some might not agree with me for the above point of view but, I feel that we have reached a stage where the law of diminishing returns makes more sense than before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I mean by that is we don&amp;rsquo;t need expensive hardware to improve the workflow. Our experience will guide us to be better and more efficient at work by utilizing the systems which we own currently. For example, if I am rendering a video and it takes around 30 minutes to do so. I could spend that 30 minutes reading a chapter of the book that I picked up while my video is getting rendered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of 2021, I have stopped playing games and, I don&amp;rsquo;t see myself playing them in the future. I have been focusing on my web development skills lately and, I could see the difference it has brought to me. I have more time at hand than before and, I could complete my daily tasks with ease.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying Out Spectrwm</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/spectrwm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 06:00:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/spectrwm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Minimal window manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my previous post about awesome wm, &lt;a href=&#34;https://fosstodon.org/@joeligj12&#34;&gt;Chrono&lt;/a&gt; suggested trying out Spectrwm. Spectrwm is a small, dynamic tiling and reparenting window manager for X11. It was for the very first time I heard about this window manager so I decided to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went with ArcoLinuxB since it has the spectrwm version available to download. The installation went fast since I didn&amp;rsquo;t install any extra packages that ArcoLinux provides during installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now coming to Spectrwm, ArcoLinux has already configured most of the stuff so I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to waste much time setting it up by myself. The keybindings are quite hard to find for a new user but since I knew where to lookup for the config I had no issues with that part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must say the window manager is quite minimal and easy to use if you remember properly the keybindings. ArcoLinux also comes with a few extra tricks at its sleeves. Such as preconfigured keybindings for most of the popular software, a key bind to change the wallpaper, and also a preconfigured polybar which is neat. It also has its own tweaks menu where you can set hblock, change the terminal theme, configure auto startup, and much more which is handy for a new user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall spectrwm can be the very first window manager for most of the new users and especially if you go with ArcoLinux since most of the stuff is already preconfigured and ready to use out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying Out Awesome WM</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/awesome-wm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 06:15:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/awesome-wm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A fast &amp;amp; easy window manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always wanted to get started with window managers, but the learning curve kept me away. So on 1st February 2021, I decided to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to mess up the primary system, I went with the virtual machine route. For the distro, I went with &lt;a href=&#34;https://manjaro.org/download/#awesome&#34;&gt;Manjaro&amp;rsquo;s community build of awesome&lt;/a&gt; after watching DistroTube&amp;rsquo;s video.

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qKtit_B7Keo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setup process was similar to that of any Manjaro installation. It took around 8-10 minutes to install, and after installation finished, the first problem I encountered was how to change the wallpaper. The easy solution was to install Nitrogen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s2.gifyu.com/images/2021-02-01-174146_2560x1080_scrot.png&#34; alt=&#34;manjaro after install&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, it took me more than 2 hours to configure the setup, according to my daily usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s2.gifyu.com/images/2021-02-01-174128_2560x1080_scrot.png&#34; alt=&#34;my setup&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of applications that I use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;URXVT (Terminal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ranger with W3M (Filemanager)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firefox (Web Browser)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rofi (Popup Window Switcher)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mousepad (GUI Text Editor)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out this video for more customization and setup.

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/nC_e8Gw1XlA&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted with my current setup, nothing too fancy or too minimal. Get&amp;rsquo;s the job done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTube-DL</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/youtube-dl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 06:00:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/youtube-dl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watch Content Offline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past few weeks, I am off from YouTube. My YouTube channel is getting mirrored on &lt;a href=&#34;https://odysee.com/&#34;&gt;Odysee&lt;/a&gt;. But I still follow my favorite content creators using Invidious, Odysee, and youtube-dl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As most of you would know, what happened with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/11/github-reinstates-youtube-dl-after-riaas-abuse-dmca&#34;&gt;repository of youtube-dl&lt;/a&gt; I am glad that it&amp;rsquo;s back and functional again. Setting up youtube-dl for the first time can be troublesome for new users, but once you get the hang of it, you would not stop, especially with config, the download process becomes easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is my config, and yes, I am on a Windows machine for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;-f mp4
-f 137+140/299+140
-o C:/Users/Joel/Downloads/YouTube/%(title)s-%(uploader)s.%(ext)s
--no-mtime
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refer &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ytdl-org/youtube-dl/blob/master/README.md#output-template&#34;&gt;Output Template&lt;/a&gt; for more details&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who wanted to get started with youtube-dl, here is a great video to begin.

&lt;iframe
  src=&#34;//invidious.kavin.rocks/embed/5axVgHHDBvU&#34;
  title=&#34;invidious player&#34;
  height=&#34;400&#34;
  frameborder=&#34;0&#34;
  marginwidth=&#34;0&#34;
  marginheight=&#34;0&#34;
  scrolling=&#34;no&#34;
  style=&#34;width: 100%&#34;
  allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;
&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My process of getting videos offline is simple. Get the link of the video from invidious and paste it into the command prompt. But if I am on my phone, I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TeamNewPipe/NewPipe&#34;&gt;Newpipe&lt;/a&gt; to watch and download YouTube videos.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create More, Consume Less</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/create/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 07:05:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/create/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People overestimate the benefits of learning by consuming things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing and learning are two seperate things but both are very powerful tools with which can help you to build your audience and opens up a new world of opportunities to you to discover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the time we consume more and think that we are learning which is hoax. Whenever we stumble upon anything which we want to learn the first step is the absorb the material and then make notes about it. Think like you will be giving a lecture about the topic which you learnt. Making notes of your own will help you to deepen the understanding of the topic, a great example of this is feynman technique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performing daily writing of what you learnt will create a reservoir of knowledge which you can then use for your success like sharing your learning with people online. This will also help you to improve your learning process because you will be getting feedback from the other people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habits are Learned</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 12:29:16 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life is made up of automatic actions called habits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I hear the term habits the first thought which comes to y mind is 21 Days, since it is know that a habit takes around 21 days to be formed or broken. Over the course of time I have read serveral books and blog post about the same but there are some core principles to be implemented in life to form habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A habit is formed from the repeated actions and the results behind is the formation of the reward. Our mind thinks that whenever we perform certain task we wil get that particular reward. Instant gratification works similarly. This also involves release of dopamine in our system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;habits-are-developed-using&#34;&gt;Habits are developed using:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cue&lt;/strong&gt; -&amp;gt; Identifies the reward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carving&lt;/strong&gt; -&amp;gt; Triggers to get the reward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Response&lt;/strong&gt; -&amp;gt; Working out towards the reward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reward&lt;/strong&gt; -&amp;gt; Satisfaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habits can be good or bad but it is upto us to decide which of our habits we want in our daily lives. To break a habit just get rid of the source. For example, for social media just hide the apps or uninstall them. The main idea is to cut the source which triggers our brain to perform that particular habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s important to choose our habits wisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://thepracticingmind.com/&#34;&gt;The Practicing Mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com/atomic-habits&#34;&gt;Atomic Habits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fRR2FSjVMPE&#34;&gt;How One Habit Changed My Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Know more about me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, I am &lt;strong&gt;Joel Rodrigues&lt;/strong&gt;, usually you can find me on internet as Kninja. I&amp;rsquo;m a 20 year web developer who also loves minimalism, privacy, anime and automobiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-of-devices-which-i-own-currently&#34;&gt;Some of devices which I own currently:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redmi Note 4 (2017 - Present)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redmi Note 7 (2019 - Present)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lenovo E41-15 (2018 - Present)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poco F1 (2019 - Present) (Daily Driver)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asus TUF A15 (2020 - Present)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>