<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>100DaysToOffload on Kninja 🌩</title>
    <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/tags/100daystooffload/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 100DaysToOffload on Kninja 🌩</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 06:00:15 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pantsufan.github.io/tags/100daystooffload/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trying Out Spectrwm</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/spectrwm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 06:00:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/spectrwm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Minimal window manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my previous post about awesome wm, &lt;a href=&#34;https://fosstodon.org/@joeligj12&#34;&gt;Chrono&lt;/a&gt; suggested trying out Spectrwm. Spectrwm is a small, dynamic tiling and reparenting window manager for X11. It was for the very first time I heard about this window manager so I decided to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went with ArcoLinuxB since it has the spectrwm version available to download. The installation went fast since I didn&amp;rsquo;t install any extra packages that ArcoLinux provides during installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now coming to Spectrwm, ArcoLinux has already configured most of the stuff so I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to waste much time setting it up by myself. The keybindings are quite hard to find for a new user but since I knew where to lookup for the config I had no issues with that part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must say the window manager is quite minimal and easy to use if you remember properly the keybindings. ArcoLinux also comes with a few extra tricks at its sleeves. Such as preconfigured keybindings for most of the popular software, a key bind to change the wallpaper, and also a preconfigured polybar which is neat. It also has its own tweaks menu where you can set hblock, change the terminal theme, configure auto startup, and much more which is handy for a new user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall spectrwm can be the very first window manager for most of the new users and especially you go with ArcoLinux since most of the stuff is already preconfigured and ready to use out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying Out Awesome WM</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/awesome-wm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 06:15:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/awesome-wm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A fast &amp;amp; easy window manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always wanted to get started with window managers, but the learning curve kept me away. So on 1st February 2021, I decided to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to mess up the primary system, I went with the virtual machine route. For the distro, I went with &lt;a href=&#34;https://manjaro.org/download/#awesome&#34;&gt;Manjaro&amp;rsquo;s community build of awesome&lt;/a&gt; after watching DistroTube&amp;rsquo;s video.

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qKtit_B7Keo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setup process was similar to that of any Manjaro installation. It took around 8-10 minutes to install, and after installation finished, the first problem I encountered was how to change the wallpaper. The easy solution was to install Nitrogen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s2.gifyu.com/images/2021-02-01-174146_2560x1080_scrot.png&#34; alt=&#34;manjaro after install&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, it took me more than 2 hours to configure the setup, according to my daily usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s2.gifyu.com/images/2021-02-01-174128_2560x1080_scrot.png&#34; alt=&#34;my setup&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of applications that I use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;URXVT (Terminal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ranger with W3M (Filemanager)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firefox (Web Browser)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rofi (Popup Window Switcher)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mousepad (GUI Text Editor)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out this video for more customization and setup.

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/nC_e8Gw1XlA&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted with my current setup, nothing too fancy or too minimal. Get&amp;rsquo;s the job done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTube-DL</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/youtube-dl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 06:00:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/youtube-dl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watch Content Offline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past few weeks, I am off from YouTube. My YouTube channel is getting mirrored on &lt;a href=&#34;https://odysee.com/&#34;&gt;Odysee&lt;/a&gt;. But I still follow my favorite content creators using Invidious, Odysee, and youtube-dl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As most of you would know, what happened with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/11/github-reinstates-youtube-dl-after-riaas-abuse-dmca&#34;&gt;repository of youtube-dl&lt;/a&gt; I am glad that it&amp;rsquo;s back and functional again. Setting up youtube-dl for the first time can be troublesome for new users, but once you get the hang of it, you would not stop, especially with config, the download process becomes easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is my config, and yes, I am on a Windows machine for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;-f mp4
-f 137+140/299+140
-o C:/Users/Joel/Downloads/YouTube/%(title)s-%(uploader)s.%(ext)s
--no-mtime
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refer &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ytdl-org/youtube-dl/blob/master/README.md#output-template&#34;&gt;Output Template&lt;/a&gt; for more details&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who wanted to get started with youtube-dl, here is a great video to begin.

&lt;iframe
  src=&#34;//invidious.kavin.rocks/embed/5axVgHHDBvU&#34;
  title=&#34;invidious player&#34;
  height=&#34;400&#34;
  frameborder=&#34;0&#34;
  marginwidth=&#34;0&#34;
  marginheight=&#34;0&#34;
  scrolling=&#34;no&#34;
  style=&#34;width: 100%&#34;
  allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;
&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My process of getting videos offline is simple. Get the link of the video from invidious and paste it into the command prompt. But if I am on my phone, I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TeamNewPipe/NewPipe&#34;&gt;Newpipe&lt;/a&gt; to watch and download YouTube videos.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create More, Consume Less</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/create/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 07:05:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/create/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People overestimate the benefits of learning by consuming things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing and learning are two seperate things but both are very powerful tools with which can help you to build your audience and opens up a new world of opportunities to you to discover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the time we consume more and think that we are learning which is hoax. Whenever we stumble upon anything which we want to learn the first step is the absorb the material and then make notes about it. Think like you will be giving a lecture about the topic which you learnt. Making notes of your own will help you to deepen the understanding of the topic, a great example of this is feynman technique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performing daily writing of what you learnt will create a reservoir of knowledge which you can then use for your success like sharing your learning with people online. This will also help you to improve your learning process because you will be getting feedback from the other people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>