<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Kninja 🌩</title>
    <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Kninja 🌩</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 09:31:05 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pantsufan.github.io/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tackling Your Major Task</title>
      <link>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/tackling-your-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 09:31:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pantsufan.github.io/post/tackling-your-tasks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Make Your Morning Productive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Twain once said&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s your job to eat a frog, it&amp;rsquo;s best to do it first thing in the morning. And If it&amp;rsquo;s your job to eat two frogs, it&amp;rsquo;s best to eat the biggest one first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-eat-a-frog&#34;&gt;How to Eat a Frog?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The frog is that one thing you have on your to-do list that is biggest and difficult to achieve and for which you don&amp;rsquo;t have any motivation. Eating the frog at the start would provide you with a sense of accomplishment at the beginning of your day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-that-damn-frog&#34;&gt;Find That Damn Frog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding the frog which, is crucial to you, can be done with the help of a simple question. What are things you don’t want to do but actually need to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;taking-action&#34;&gt;Taking Action&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, my biggest, frog was to practice web development. Ever since I started to do it as the first thing after waking up I could get a lot of stuff done in a short period of time. Interestingly enough I have also noticed that I  am in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kj1hLFSORTQ&#34;&gt;state of flow&lt;/a&gt; and I don&amp;rsquo;t have any sense of time whats so ever. My day usually begins at 6 AM and for the next 2 hours, I am on my laptop either doing web development or reading on topics that interest me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned that practice is the key to mastering any skill. Tackling your major task first thing each morning will help you stay focused, productive, and motivated to achieve more. Eat that damn frog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>